theranos.com 2012-11-15

# Theranos - Privacy Policy

### Theranos Privacy Policy

Theranos understands that privacy is important and has created this Privacy Policy in order to communicate its policies and practices relating to information collected on or through the Theranos Website. Throughout this Privacy Policy, “Theranos” and “We” refers to Theranos, Inc. “You” or “Users” refers to you or our users — everyone who uses or visits Theranos.com. The “Theranos Website” refers to the website located at theranos.com (and any subdomains thereof) and information provided by Theranos at this website.

By using the Theranos Website, you expressly consent to the information handling practices described in this notice. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and is subject to the Theranos Website Terms of Use. Your use of the Theranos Website and any personal information you provide through the Theranos Website are subject at all times to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use.

  1. #### The Information Theranos Collects

    * ##### Information You Provide:

The Theranos Website does not collect or solicit any personal information during use or access to the Theranos Website. However, you can provide to Theranos what is generally called “personally-identifiable” information (such as your name, email address, postal mailing address, and telephone numbers) only if you choose to contact Theranos via email from the website or by submitting your résumé for the open positions at Theranos listed under the “Careers” section of the Theranos Website. 
    * ##### “Cookies” Information:

When you access the Theranos Website, we may send one or more cookies – small text files containing a string of alpha-numeric characters – to your computer. Theranos may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Theranos Website. Persistent cookies can be removed. Please review your web browser “Help” file to learn the best way to modify your cookie settings. 
    * ##### “Automatically Collected” Information:

When you access the Theranos Website we may automatically record certain information from your system by using different types of tracking technology. This “automatically collected” information may include Internet Protocol address (“IP Address”), versions of software installed, system type, the content and pages that you access on the Theranos Website, and the dates and times that you visit the Theranos Website.

  2. The Way Theranos Uses Information

    * Theranos uses the information that we collect to operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features and services found on the Theranos Website, as well as to comply with applicable laws. 
    * We will not use, without your further consent, your email address or other contact information you may choose to provide when contacting Theranos via email, except to respond to your initial email.
    * Theranos uses all of the information that we collect to understand the usage trends and preferences of our Users, to improve the way the Theranos Website works and looks, and to create new features and functionality. 
    * Theranos may use “Automatically Collected” information and “Cookies” information to: (a) automatically update the Theranos Website on your system; and (b) monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages accessed.

  3. When Theranos Discloses Information

    * Theranos does not share your personally-identifiable information with other organizations for their marketing or promotional uses without your prior express consent. 
    * We may disclose some Automatically Collected and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information to affiliated companies or other businesses or persons to: provide website hosting, maintenance, and security services; conduct data analysis and create reports; offer certain functionality; and assist Theranos in improving the Theranos Website and creating new services features. We require that these parties process such information in compliance with this Privacy Policy. We authorize only a limited use of such information for the listed purpose, and we require these parties to use reasonable confidentiality measures.
    * Theranos may disclose User information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws (such as U.S. copyright law) or respond to a court order, judicial or other government subpoena, or warrant in the manner required by the requesting entity.
    * Theranos also reserves the right to disclose User information that we believe, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to take precautions against liability; protect Theranos from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; to investigate and defend ourselves against third-party claims or allegations; to assist government enforcement agencies; to protect the security or integrity of the Theranos Website; or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Theranos, our Users, or others.

  4. Your Choices

If you do not contact Theranos by email, then your use of the Theranos Website will not provide your personally-identifiable information to Theranos.

  5. Data Security

Theranos uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Theranos, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, Theranos makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. 

If Theranos learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. Theranos may post a notice on the Theranos Website if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive a free written notice of a security breach you should notify us at privacy@theranos.com.

  6. Children’s Privacy

If you are under 13 years of age, then please do not email or contact Theranos at any time or in any manner. 

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, Theranos does not knowingly collect or maintain personally-identifiable information from persons under 13 years-of-age. If Theranos learns that personally-identifiable information of persons less than 13-years-of-age has been provided to Theranos, then Theranos will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. 

If you are the parent or legal guardian of a child under 13 who has provided personal information to Theranos, then please contact Theranos at info@theranos.com to have that child’s information deleted.

  7. International Visitors

For Users visiting the Theranos Website from the European Economic Area or other non-U.S. territories, please note that any data you send in an email to the Theranos Website will be transferred outside the European Economic Area or such other non-U.S. territory for use by Theranos and its affiliated companies for any of the purposes described herein. In addition, because Theranos operates globally, we may make information we gather available to worldwide business units and affiliated companies. By providing any data on the Theranos Website, you hereby expressly consent to such transfers of your data to the United States or other countries.

  8. In the Event of Merger or Sale

In the event that Theranos is acquired by or merged with a third-party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from the Theranos Website as part of that merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control.

  9. Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy may be revised periodically without further notice to you and this will be reflected by a “last modified” date below. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. In general, we only use your personal information in the manner described in the Privacy Policy in effect when we received that personal information. Your continued use of the Theranos Website constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any future revisions.

For revisions to this Privacy Policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of personal information you have provided to us, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you and obtain your consent before implementing revisions with respect to such information.

  10.   11. Theranos Contact Information

Please contact Theranos with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, your personal information, and our third-party disclosure practices or your consent choices by email to the Theranos email address on our Contact page. We will respond to your inquiry within thirty (30) days of its receipt.
